

ALEJANDRO PLOTNO

Creative Designer

Catch a glimpse of a current project in:



ABOUT ME

Hi! My name is Ale and I work in digital design. UX and UI are my main interests and where I have most of my experience. I started as a freelance web and graphic designer, eventually making the leap to the planning and strategizing roles but never losing sight of the customers' journey while navigating our products.

Currently I'm studying react and a unity to further my knowledge in those areas. I'm constantly learning about UX and UI to keep myself up to date.



CONTACT ME



Amenábar 1121 6to A, Buenos Aires, Argentina



aplotno@gmail.com



+541141960031



MY SKILLS



Adobe Suite (Ai, Ph, Pr, Id)



Web Development (CMS, HTML, CSS, JS)



3D Modelling & Animation (3DS, Rhino)



3D Printing (Qura)



Analytics & Performance



WORK EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL DESIGNER

Tachyus - October 2018 - To date

Currently I'm involved in several projects (UI, web design, brochure design) for Tachyus, a start up dealing with optimizing oil production via machine learning.

MARKETING & DESIGN MANAGER

Creal - February 2017 - October 2018

In this position I dealt mainly with everything regarding design, online marketing and managing the company's online presence. I also oversaw the development of a new ecommerce

FREELANCE WEB DESIGN

Freelance - March 2014 - To date

As a freelance designer I've been involved in designing, mantaining, deploying and updating several websites for different clients.

ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER

DEMASLED - March 2012 - January 2017

In this company I was mainly tasked with heading the design department and the online part of the marketing department. I oversaw the team that was in charge of planning and carrying out the advertising campaings, mailing list, social media, adwords and websites. During my tenure the website, which contained no e-commerce was completely rehauled and updated to include a store. This was done on a custom CMS for five different locations around the world.



EDUCATION

UX/UI DESIGN

JAVASCRIPT - REACT

Coursera - March 2018 - June 2019

Codeacademy - July 2019 - To date

GRAPHIC DESIGN

ORT Argentina- March 2016 - February 2018

Even though I was filling roles as a web designer with my earlier training, I felt that it could be beneficial to receive a formal training in this area.

It is very helpful for approaching a new design and I feel it improved considerably my use of white space.

PRODUCT DESIGN

ORT Argentina - March 2010 - February 2014

Although I'm not centered on designing physical products anymore, in these course of studies I was shown the basics of design with a heavy emphasis on usability.

Illustration, 3D modelling and animation are also skills that proved very useful while building sites. I feel I can provide plenty of different options that can be considered for arriving at a specific style.



LANGUAGES



SPANISH Native



Advanced



ALEJANDRO PLOTNO Diseño Web

Para ver algún proyecto en desarrollo: https://aplotno.github.io



SOBRE MÍ

¡Hola! Mi nombre es Ale y me desenvuelvo en todo lo que tenga que ver con diseño. Más que nada en diseño de interfaces y experiencia del usuario. Comencé como diseñador web y gráfico, eventualmente llegando a posiciones más de planeamiento y estrategia pero nunca perdiendo de vista el customer journey mientras interactúa con nuestros productos.

Actualmente estoy estudiando react y unity para expandir mi conocimiento en esas áreas. Constantemente me actualizo sobre las úlitmas novedades en todo lo que es UX y UI.



CONTACTO



Amenábar 1121 6to A, Buenos Aires, Argentina



aplotno@gmail.com



+541141960031



CONOCIMIENTOS



Adobe Suite (Ai, Ph, Pr, Id)



Diseño Web (CMS, HTML, CSS, JS)



Modelado 3D (3DS, Rhino)



Impresión 3D (Qura)



Analytics & Performance



WORK EXPERIENCE

DISEÑADOR DIGITAL

Tachyus - Octubre 2018 - Actual

Actualmente me encuentro realizando diversos proyectos (UI, web design, diseño de brochures técnicos) para Tachyus, una start-up dedicada al machine learning aplicado a la optimización de la extracción de petróleo.

ENCARGADO MARKETING ONLINE Y DISEÑO

Creal - Febrero 2017 - Octubre 2018

En esta cadena de comercios me encargué principalmente de todo lo que es imágen, diseño y marketing online. En adición a esto me concentré en el desarrollo y armado de un nuevo e-commerce en combinación con developers externos

DISEÑO WEB FREELANCE

Freelance - Mayo 2014 - Actual

He realizado diversos proyectos en modalidad freelance relacionados con páginas web: Diseño, armado, mantenimiento y deployment.

ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER

DEMASLED - Marzo 2012 - Enero 2017

En este puesto llevaba adelante el departamento de marketing online y diseño. Entre mis responsabilidades estaban el manejo de la comunicación (mailings, redes, adwords) así como el armado, control y mantenimiento de la página web y los catálogos. Durante mi estadía allí se rehizo el sitio web desde cero para incluir un ecommerce con un CMS custom para 5 locaciones alrededor del mundo.



EDUCATION

JAVASCRIPT - REACT

DISEÑO UX/UI

Codeacademy - Julio 2019 - Actual

Coursera - Marzo 2018 - Junio 2019

DISEÑO GRÁFICO

ORT Argentina- Marzo 2016 - Febrero 2018

Si bien ocupé puestos de diseño web previamente creo que el entrenamiento formal en el área es una necesidad fundamental para generar mejores piezas.

A partir de esto, creo que fui adquiriendo herramientas esenciales para comenzar cualquier tipo de diseño y mejoró mucho mi utilización de los espacios vacios.

DISEÑO DE PRODUCTOS

ORT Argentina - Marzo 2010 - Febrero 2014

Aunque actualmente no estoy enfocado en la generación de productos físicos, aquí pude aprender las bases del diseño centrado en la usabilidad. Este conocimiento lo sigo aplicando al día de hoy al desarrollar una interfaz y una experiencia de usuario.

El modelado 3D, animación e ilustración son herramientas muy útiles a la hora de desarrollar un sitio. Creo que proveen muchas opciones a la hora de elegir un estilo específico y concretarlo.



LANGUAGES



ESPAÑOL Nativo

